<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: The Revolving Door of Governement and Corporations AKA Fascism.	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/</link>
	<description>Exegesis Hermeneutics Flux Capacitor of Truthiness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:54:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: The Revolving Door of Government and Corporations AKA #Fascism. #CovidPurpose #Think #ArethaFranklin #RedemptionSong #BobMarley #Yaah #Love #Peace #COVIDPURPOSE AND #COVIDPROPAGANDA . @DAVIDGRAEBER @FINANCIALEYES @JOEBLOB20 #DEBTBOMB @DOMINICFRISBY &#8211		</title>
		<link>/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/comment-page-1/#comment-11206</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Revolving Door of Government and Corporations AKA #Fascism. #CovidPurpose #Think #ArethaFranklin #RedemptionSong #BobMarley #Yaah #Love #Peace #COVIDPURPOSE AND #COVIDPROPAGANDA . @DAVIDGRAEBER @FINANCIALEYES @JOEBLOB20 #DEBTBOMB @DOMINICFRISBY &#8211]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism#comment-11206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] The Revolving Door of Governement and Corporations AKA Fascism.Dumping of toxic waste in the UKBetwe&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] The Revolving Door of Governement and Corporations AKA Fascism.Dumping of toxic waste in the UKBetwe&#8230; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Our only debt is to Nature and &#8216;What Is&#8217;. Environmental Pragmatism, Live and let live. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/comment-page-1/#comment-2989</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Our only debt is to Nature and &#8216;What Is&#8217;. Environmental Pragmatism, Live and let live. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 07:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism#comment-2989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] into the Bounties of Goldman Sachs shows the transatlantic extent of this Elitist revolving door. Again this has been going on for a long time.     I wonder if Mr.Trump will withdraw the US fatwah upon Mr. Assange. Pardon Mr. Edward Snowden and [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] into the Bounties of Goldman Sachs shows the transatlantic extent of this Elitist revolving door. Again this has been going on for a long time.     I wonder if Mr.Trump will withdraw the US fatwah upon Mr. Assange. Pardon Mr. Edward Snowden and [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Gate Keepers Double Agents False Trails. The Topsy Turvy Helter Skelter of The International Lies Based Order. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/comment-page-1/#comment-1168</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gate Keepers Double Agents False Trails. The Topsy Turvy Helter Skelter of The International Lies Based Order. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 02:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism#comment-1168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporation&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporation&#038;#8230" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporation&#038;#8230</a>; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: RogerGLewis		</title>
		<link>/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism/comment-page-1/#comment-12</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[RogerGLewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 06:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2011/06/25/the-revolving-door-of-governement-and-corporations-aka-fascism#comment-12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Umberto Eco&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a 1995 essay &quot;Eternal Fascism&quot;,[21] the Italian writer and academic Umberto Eco attempts to list general properties of fascist ideology. He claims that it is not possible to organise these into a coherent system, but that &quot;it is enough that one of them be present to allow fascism to coagulate around it&quot;. He uses the term &quot;Ur-fascism&quot; as a generic description of different historical forms of fascism.&lt;br /&gt;The features of fascism he lists are as follows:&lt;br /&gt;&quot;The Cult of Tradition&quot;, combining cultural syncretism with a rejection of modernism (often disguised as a rejection of capitalism).&lt;br /&gt;&quot;The Cult of Action for Action&#039;s Sake&quot;, which dictates that action is of value in itself, and should be taken without intellectual reflection. This, says Eco, is connected with anti-intellectualism and irrationalism, and often manifests in attacks on modern culture and science.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Disagreement Is Treason&quot; - fascism devalues intellectual discourse and critical reasoning as barriers to action.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Fear of Difference&quot;, which fascism seeks to exploit and exacerbate, often in the form of racism or an appeal against foreigners and immigrants.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Appeal to a Frustrated Middle Class&quot;, fearing economic pressure from the demands and aspirations of lower social groups.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Obsession with a Plot&quot; and the hyping-up of an enemy threat. This often involves an appeal to xenophobia or the identification of an internal security threat. He cites Pat Robertson&#039;s book The New World Order as a prominent example of a plot obsession.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Pacifism Is Trafficking with the Enemy&quot; because &quot;Life is Permanent Warfare&quot; - there must always be an enemy to fight.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Contempt for the Weak&quot; - although a fascist society is elitist, everybody in the society is educated to become a hero.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Selective Populism&quot; - the People have a common will, which is not delegated but interpreted by a leader. This may involve doubt being cast upon a democratic institution, because &quot;it no longer represents the Voice of the People&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&quot;Newspeak&quot; - fascism employs and promotes an impoverished vocabulary in order to limit critical reasoning.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Umberto Eco</p>
<p>In a 1995 essay &#8220;Eternal Fascism&#8221;,[21] the Italian writer and academic Umberto Eco attempts to list general properties of fascist ideology. He claims that it is not possible to organise these into a coherent system, but that &#8220;it is enough that one of them be present to allow fascism to coagulate around it&#8221;. He uses the term &#8220;Ur-fascism&#8221; as a generic description of different historical forms of fascism.<br />The features of fascism he lists are as follows:<br />&#8220;The Cult of Tradition&#8221;, combining cultural syncretism with a rejection of modernism (often disguised as a rejection of capitalism).<br />&#8220;The Cult of Action for Action&#39;s Sake&#8221;, which dictates that action is of value in itself, and should be taken without intellectual reflection. This, says Eco, is connected with anti-intellectualism and irrationalism, and often manifests in attacks on modern culture and science.<br />&#8220;Disagreement Is Treason&#8221; &#8211; fascism devalues intellectual discourse and critical reasoning as barriers to action.<br />&#8220;Fear of Difference&#8221;, which fascism seeks to exploit and exacerbate, often in the form of racism or an appeal against foreigners and immigrants.<br />&#8220;Appeal to a Frustrated Middle Class&#8221;, fearing economic pressure from the demands and aspirations of lower social groups.<br />&#8220;Obsession with a Plot&#8221; and the hyping-up of an enemy threat. This often involves an appeal to xenophobia or the identification of an internal security threat. He cites Pat Robertson&#39;s book The New World Order as a prominent example of a plot obsession.<br />&#8220;Pacifism Is Trafficking with the Enemy&#8221; because &#8220;Life is Permanent Warfare&#8221; &#8211; there must always be an enemy to fight.<br />&#8220;Contempt for the Weak&#8221; &#8211; although a fascist society is elitist, everybody in the society is educated to become a hero.<br />&#8220;Selective Populism&#8221; &#8211; the People have a common will, which is not delegated but interpreted by a leader. This may involve doubt being cast upon a democratic institution, because &#8220;it no longer represents the Voice of the People&#8221;.<br />&#8220;Newspeak&#8221; &#8211; fascism employs and promotes an impoverished vocabulary in order to limit critical reasoning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
