<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: World Premiere Performance of Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony.	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/</link>
	<description>Exegesis Hermeneutics Flux Capacitor of Truthiness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 05:53:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Full Spectrum Imperialism which we could call Globalism for short. The Hierarchy That Enslaves You #THEY #Covidstroika &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-12320</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Full Spectrum Imperialism which we could call Globalism for short. The Hierarchy That Enslaves You #THEY #Covidstroika &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 05:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-12320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0 Cricket Appleseed  Published on 15 Apr 2016 Everything that was directly lived has receded into representation. Original File: https://vimeo.com/60328678  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY The Society of the Spectacle by Guy Debord (1973) dub fr sub eng Augustine Joyce ublished on 7 Jan 2013 La Société du Spectacle (Society of the Spectacle) is a black and white 1973 film by the Situationist Guy Debord based on his 1967 book of the same title. It was Debord&#8217;s first feature-length film. It uses found footage and detournement in a radical criticism of mass marketing and its role in the alienation of modern society.   The 88 minute film took a year to make and incorporates footage from feature films, industrial films, news footage, advertisements, and still photographs.[1] The films include The Battleship Potemkin, October, Chapaev, The New Babylon, The Shanghai Gesture, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Rio Grande, They Died with Their Boots On, Johnny Guitar, and Mr. Arkadin, as well as other Soviet films.  A PDF form in tabulated format is available as the poem is concieved as a Matrix which can be read in columns as single voices or sequentiually as a dialogue. The PDF will be available for download for Patreon subscribers or customers on Amazon. The formatting for the downloads will be completed hopefully by the end of this weekend.         Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony.  Synthesis Speaks to introduce, And Thesis, Anti Thesis and Synthesis dialogue The conversation revolves and we find  Revolution plagiarizes past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and entreat your contribution dear reader for a fourth part, shall we harmonIse.  Synthesis.  Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature. ∲6/8 bb :  Thesis.  In a diary of a nobody, Mr Pooter, is everyman and woman. Striving. Petit Bourgeois, discordant with their lot, in earnest to impress.  Anti Thesis  Life liberty and the pursuit of happiness,  inalienable rights , the laws of Nature  and of natures god.A constitution  written for a usurping class, claiming  authority, a reflection of common sense,  and pained to see. This revolution of , by and for Whom? Synthesis. As the victor writes history so the powerful pass laws to satisfy their own ends. Power only represents the powerful.   Moyenne Bourgeoise and Grande Haute Bourgeoise. A Class cuisine, Escoffier Classical Aspiration. One acquires,  A bourgeoise aesthetic, Petit Bourgeoise Sycophancy.   Will the Chef of the constitution, Taste his own cooking. Does he as a class walk the walk and talk the talk Or is it ; do as I say and not as I do.  An appeal always made, at once  to Authority.Follow faithfully, blindly.  Ask they who would your bidding do. Listen to your life&#8217;s story, History, His History will not be yours? Be heard.   Pygmalion&#8217;s elocution for the ordinaire. Les rois et philosophes merde-et  ainsi de faire des dames. Conventional pieties of the extraordinaire, Elite.  Écoute Et Répète, Listen and repeat Learn by rote and do not question, To Each that has shall be given,  those who hath not will be punished, Know ones betters and issue scripted  speech when spoken too, Obsequious.  Do not blanche before appearance of grandeur. Pompous ceremony seeks to silence chafing curiosity.     How readily the pecking order has regiments in line , volunteers  to a false consciousness of liberation by  societies consumptive ills, Polysemous  At the sign, Obey and join the  que. Wait your turn and receive  your due. Punch the clock and Answer the bell. Ask not for whom the bell tolls, The bell rings the benefit makes a gift of what is rightfully yours.  The hand that gives also takes away. Often the gift merely returns that which was stolen from you.     Citizens within a polity, city state yet the peasants range free of sophistry  Freemen in the confined spaces offer conformity to the graduated mould.  Glamorous flashing city lights Suburbia within commute of higher Dreams. A stairway to real Estate heaven.The only Ladder, oh to be upon the bottom rung and rise.Dreams for mortgage, no hostage to Fortune.  Sophistication often masques ignorance. The humble and rustic often belies an appreciation of what truly is.     Calliopsis or Magnesia where poets slave to familiar rhymes and themes Not golden or silver words but workmanlike  fashion hymns of safe iron and copper.  On The city on the hill, Songs sung to green and pleasant lands My Country Right or wrong Patriotic duty, above the evidence heroic deeds, laurels earned Myths of Wagnerian operatic spectacle.  Behind the claimed reality of how things are lies a deeper truth clothed in the noble lie. He deceived by the noble lie is excluded as unworthy of an opinion.     Where Stockholm once commanded St-Petersberg in that peculiar syndrome did the people know of freedom, which noble lies  will accommodate the others&#8217;, too Slumber.  A common purpose, to ideals,Shared  and narrated from Cradle to grave. History written in our victorious mood Always times distant, always yesterday A better day , a past nostalgic searching For a future, yet to become tomorrow.  Being keen to please and seeking approval from authority feeds ego and starves the real self.  An irony of words pretending a meaning which no longer holds and yet serves to bind a convention, a grip that hampers the gait, Barre the pedestrian.  Witty Double entrendre to pacify, Laughing at the otherness, not of our own genre. Bending of wills or an ends of a means which makes  a meaner mind , setting examples Cruelty for kindness sake, who´s End?  The devil takes the hindmost. Trampling upon the unfortunate excuses elitist privilege. There but for the grace of privilege go they!     Self censored by a Mean temperament no longer just and a bespoke Key The city gates envelop to constrain Invention no longer a prize, only too fit.  Which mode of government befitting The cadence of Timocracy, Oligarchy or the tyranny of democracy, Which? A key to unlock the wealth of timbre Trusting in the chastity of greed the diabolas in musica. Descend below.  Discord or overbalance corrects naturally. In a system where gross imbalance and discord is evident are we to believe that harmony was ever thus.  As poets slave to the set rythym  so a ruling Class Slaves to support  its very tyranny, no purpose theirs, tis only to own be owned and Owe.  There is no Alternative, leave behind your utopian dreams of youth, Grown, reality demands that you sing Our  democratic song making it your own.  No third , way. Just the chord of power.  Ambiguous, A Capitalist mode production.  Power is an end in itself. Seeking power to reform injustice is a contradiction in terms. For harmonious consensus all voices must strike a chord.    Oh such discordance felt heard seen  demanding resolution. Harmonies equal  in temperament to guide back home to the unity. One full revolution  Tracing the musical image in  Camra obscura, inverted and opposite, do you see what it is yet As the tonic marks a tranquil resting place so conformity leaves us resolved resiled and not reconciled Trapped  Power relations beget power relations, As the wheel of history turns repeating mistakes of previous revolutions.  As the wheel turns a revolution as a harmony resolves Resolution A new hub for human consciousness. Not the machine now but organic.  Yours to follow little people Know your place and praise Elite heroes, distant an shimmering As all mirages inspire the thirsty  to crawl into the oasis of illusion squeezing blood from exhausted humanity.   As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature.    The conversation has revolved and we find  Revolution plagiarized its past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and with your contribution dear reader a fourth part, harmonIsed. Or perhaps we as yet have to find a resolution , play on and seek new voices for our symphony of freedom is not yet written and least wise played freely with authentic joy.  Others we invite TO ,   Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0</a> Cricket Appleseed  Published on 15 Apr 2016 Everything that was directly lived has receded into representation. Original File:</p>
<div class="embed-vimeo" style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/60328678" width="708" height="398" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY</a> The Society of the Spectacle by Guy Debord (1973) dub fr sub eng Augustine Joyce ublished on 7 Jan 2013 La Société du Spectacle (Society of the Spectacle) is a black and white 1973 film by the Situationist Guy Debord based on his 1967 book of the same title. It was Debord&#8217;s first feature-length film. It uses found footage and detournement in a radical criticism of mass marketing and its role in the alienation of modern society.   The 88 minute film took a year to make and incorporates footage from feature films, industrial films, news footage, advertisements, and still photographs.[1] The films include The Battleship Potemkin, October, Chapaev, The New Babylon, The Shanghai Gesture, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Rio Grande, They Died with Their Boots On, Johnny Guitar, and Mr. Arkadin, as well as other Soviet films.  A PDF form in tabulated format is available as the poem is concieved as a Matrix which can be read in columns as single voices or sequentiually as a dialogue. The PDF will be available for download for Patreon subscribers or customers on Amazon. The formatting for the downloads will be completed hopefully by the end of this weekend.         Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony.  Synthesis Speaks to introduce, And Thesis, Anti Thesis and Synthesis dialogue The conversation revolves and we find  Revolution plagiarizes past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and entreat your contribution dear reader for a fourth part, shall we harmonIse.  Synthesis.  Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature. ∲6/8 bb :  Thesis.  In a diary of a nobody, Mr Pooter, is everyman and woman. Striving. Petit Bourgeois, discordant with their lot, in earnest to impress.  Anti Thesis  Life liberty and the pursuit of happiness,  inalienable rights , the laws of Nature  and of natures god.A constitution  written for a usurping class, claiming  authority, a reflection of common sense,  and pained to see. This revolution of , by and for Whom? Synthesis. As the victor writes history so the powerful pass laws to satisfy their own ends. Power only represents the powerful.   Moyenne Bourgeoise and Grande Haute Bourgeoise. A Class cuisine, Escoffier Classical Aspiration. One acquires,  A bourgeoise aesthetic, Petit Bourgeoise Sycophancy.   Will the Chef of the constitution, Taste his own cooking. Does he as a class walk the walk and talk the talk Or is it ; do as I say and not as I do.  An appeal always made, at once  to Authority.Follow faithfully, blindly.  Ask they who would your bidding do. Listen to your life&#8217;s story, History, His History will not be yours? Be heard.   Pygmalion&#8217;s elocution for the ordinaire. Les rois et philosophes merde-et  ainsi de faire des dames. Conventional pieties of the extraordinaire, Elite.  Écoute Et Répète, Listen and repeat Learn by rote and do not question, To Each that has shall be given,  those who hath not will be punished, Know ones betters and issue scripted  speech when spoken too, Obsequious.  Do not blanche before appearance of grandeur. Pompous ceremony seeks to silence chafing curiosity.     How readily the pecking order has regiments in line , volunteers  to a false consciousness of liberation by  societies consumptive ills, Polysemous  At the sign, Obey and join the  que. Wait your turn and receive  your due. Punch the clock and Answer the bell. Ask not for whom the bell tolls, The bell rings the benefit makes a gift of what is rightfully yours.  The hand that gives also takes away. Often the gift merely returns that which was stolen from you.     Citizens within a polity, city state yet the peasants range free of sophistry  Freemen in the confined spaces offer conformity to the graduated mould.  Glamorous flashing city lights Suburbia within commute of higher Dreams. A stairway to real Estate heaven.The only Ladder, oh to be upon the bottom rung and rise.Dreams for mortgage, no hostage to Fortune.  Sophistication often masques ignorance. The humble and rustic often belies an appreciation of what truly is.     Calliopsis or Magnesia where poets slave to familiar rhymes and themes Not golden or silver words but workmanlike  fashion hymns of safe iron and copper.  On The city on the hill, Songs sung to green and pleasant lands My Country Right or wrong Patriotic duty, above the evidence heroic deeds, laurels earned Myths of Wagnerian operatic spectacle.  Behind the claimed reality of how things are lies a deeper truth clothed in the noble lie. He deceived by the noble lie is excluded as unworthy of an opinion.     Where Stockholm once commanded St-Petersberg in that peculiar syndrome did the people know of freedom, which noble lies  will accommodate the others&#8217;, too Slumber.  A common purpose, to ideals,Shared  and narrated from Cradle to grave. History written in our victorious mood Always times distant, always yesterday A better day , a past nostalgic searching For a future, yet to become tomorrow.  Being keen to please and seeking approval from authority feeds ego and starves the real self.  An irony of words pretending a meaning which no longer holds and yet serves to bind a convention, a grip that hampers the gait, Barre the pedestrian.  Witty Double entrendre to pacify, Laughing at the otherness, not of our own genre. Bending of wills or an ends of a means which makes  a meaner mind , setting examples Cruelty for kindness sake, who´s End?  The devil takes the hindmost. Trampling upon the unfortunate excuses elitist privilege. There but for the grace of privilege go they!     Self censored by a Mean temperament no longer just and a bespoke Key The city gates envelop to constrain Invention no longer a prize, only too fit.  Which mode of government befitting The cadence of Timocracy, Oligarchy or the tyranny of democracy, Which? A key to unlock the wealth of timbre Trusting in the chastity of greed the diabolas in musica. Descend below.  Discord or overbalance corrects naturally. In a system where gross imbalance and discord is evident are we to believe that harmony was ever thus.  As poets slave to the set rythym  so a ruling Class Slaves to support  its very tyranny, no purpose theirs, tis only to own be owned and Owe.  There is no Alternative, leave behind your utopian dreams of youth, Grown, reality demands that you sing Our  democratic song making it your own.  No third , way. Just the chord of power.  Ambiguous, A Capitalist mode production.  Power is an end in itself. Seeking power to reform injustice is a contradiction in terms. For harmonious consensus all voices must strike a chord.    Oh such discordance felt heard seen  demanding resolution. Harmonies equal  in temperament to guide back home to the unity. One full revolution  Tracing the musical image in  Camra obscura, inverted and opposite, do you see what it is yet As the tonic marks a tranquil resting place so conformity leaves us resolved resiled and not reconciled Trapped  Power relations beget power relations, As the wheel of history turns repeating mistakes of previous revolutions.  As the wheel turns a revolution as a harmony resolves Resolution A new hub for human consciousness. Not the machine now but organic.  Yours to follow little people Know your place and praise Elite heroes, distant an shimmering As all mirages inspire the thirsty  to crawl into the oasis of illusion squeezing blood from exhausted humanity.   As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature.    The conversation has revolved and we find  Revolution plagiarized its past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and with your contribution dear reader a fourth part, harmonIsed. Or perhaps we as yet have to find a resolution , play on and seek new voices for our symphony of freedom is not yet written and least wise played freely with authentic joy.  Others we invite TO ,   Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    <a href="http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html" rel="nofollow ugc">http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html</a> [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony. &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-12316</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony. &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 05:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-12316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0 Cricket Appleseed  Published on 15 Apr 2016 Everything that was directly lived has receded into representation. Original File: https://vimeo.com/60328678  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY The Society of the Spectacle by Guy Debord (1973) dub fr sub eng Augustine Joyce ublished on 7 Jan 2013 La Société du Spectacle (Society of the Spectacle) is a black and white 1973 film by the Situationist Guy Debord based on his 1967 book of the same title. It was Debord&#8217;s first feature-length film. It uses found footage and detournement in a radical criticism of mass marketing and its role in the alienation of modern society.   The 88 minute film took a year to make and incorporates footage from feature films, industrial films, news footage, advertisements, and still photographs.[1] The films include The Battleship Potemkin, October, Chapaev, The New Babylon, The Shanghai Gesture, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Rio Grande, They Died with Their Boots On, Johnny Guitar, and Mr. Arkadin, as well as other Soviet films.  A PDF form in tabulated format is available as the poem is concieved as a Matrix which can be read in columns as single voices or sequentiually as a dialogue. The PDF will be available for download for Patreon subscribers or customers on Amazon. The formatting for the downloads will be completed hopefully by the end of this weekend.         Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony.  Synthesis Speaks to introduce, And Thesis, Anti Thesis and Synthesis dialogue The conversation revolves and we find  Revolution plagiarizes past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and entreat your contribution dear reader for a fourth part, shall we harmonIse.  Synthesis.  Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature. ∲6/8 bb :  Thesis.  In a diary of a nobody, Mr Pooter, is everyman and woman. Striving. Petit Bourgeois, discordant with their lot, in earnest to impress.  Anti Thesis  Life liberty and the pursuit of happiness,  inalienable rights , the laws of Nature  and of natures god.A constitution  written for a usurping class, claiming  authority, a reflection of common sense,  and pained to see. This revolution of , by and for Whom? Synthesis. As the victor writes history so the powerful pass laws to satisfy their own ends. Power only represents the powerful.   Moyenne Bourgeoise and Grande Haute Bourgeoise. A Class cuisine, Escoffier Classical Aspiration. One acquires,  A bourgeoise aesthetic, Petit Bourgeoise Sycophancy.   Will the Chef of the constitution, Taste his own cooking. Does he as a class walk the walk and talk the talk Or is it ; do as I say and not as I do.  An appeal always made, at once  to Authority.Follow faithfully, blindly.  Ask they who would your bidding do. Listen to your life&#8217;s story, History, His History will not be yours? Be heard.   Pygmalion&#8217;s elocution for the ordinaire. Les rois et philosophes merde-et  ainsi de faire des dames. Conventional pieties of the extraordinaire, Elite.  Écoute Et Répète, Listen and repeat Learn by rote and do not question, To Each that has shall be given,  those who hath not will be punished, Know ones betters and issue scripted  speech when spoken too, Obsequious.  Do not blanche before appearance of grandeur. Pompous ceremony seeks to silence chafing curiosity.     How readily the pecking order has regiments in line , volunteers  to a false consciousness of liberation by  societies consumptive ills, Polysemous  At the sign, Obey and join the  que. Wait your turn and receive  your due. Punch the clock and Answer the bell. Ask not for whom the bell tolls, The bell rings the benefit makes a gift of what is rightfully yours.  The hand that gives also takes away. Often the gift merely returns that which was stolen from you.     Citizens within a polity, city state yet the peasants range free of sophistry  Freemen in the confined spaces offer conformity to the graduated mould.  Glamorous flashing city lights Suburbia within commute of higher Dreams. A stairway to real Estate heaven.The only Ladder, oh to be upon the bottom rung and rise.Dreams for mortgage, no hostage to Fortune.  Sophistication often masques ignorance. The humble and rustic often belies an appreciation of what truly is.     Calliopsis or Magnesia where poets slave to familiar rhymes and themes Not golden or silver words but workmanlike  fashion hymns of safe iron and copper.  On The city on the hill, Songs sung to green and pleasant lands My Country Right or wrong Patriotic duty, above the evidence heroic deeds, laurels earned Myths of Wagnerian operatic spectacle.  Behind the claimed reality of how things are lies a deeper truth clothed in the noble lie. He deceived by the noble lie is excluded as unworthy of an opinion.     Where Stockholm once commanded St-Petersberg in that peculiar syndrome did the people know of freedom, which noble lies  will accommodate the others&#8217;, too Slumber.  A common purpose, to ideals,Shared  and narrated from Cradle to grave. History written in our victorious mood Always times distant, always yesterday A better day , a past nostalgic searching For a future, yet to become tomorrow.  Being keen to please and seeking approval from authority feeds ego and starves the real self.  An irony of words pretending a meaning which no longer holds and yet serves to bind a convention, a grip that hampers the gait, Barre the pedestrian.  Witty Double entrendre to pacify, Laughing at the otherness, not of our own genre. Bending of wills or an ends of a means which makes  a meaner mind , setting examples Cruelty for kindness sake, who´s End?  The devil takes the hindmost. Trampling upon the unfortunate excuses elitist privilege. There but for the grace of privilege go they!     Self censored by a Mean temperament no longer just and a bespoke Key The city gates envelop to constrain Invention no longer a prize, only too fit.  Which mode of government befitting The cadence of Timocracy, Oligarchy or the tyranny of democracy, Which? A key to unlock the wealth of timbre Trusting in the chastity of greed the diabolas in musica. Descend below.  Discord or overbalance corrects naturally. In a system where gross imbalance and discord is evident are we to believe that harmony was ever thus.  As poets slave to the set rythym  so a ruling Class Slaves to support  its very tyranny, no purpose theirs, tis only to own be owned and Owe.  There is no Alternative, leave behind your utopian dreams of youth, Grown, reality demands that you sing Our  democratic song making it your own.  No third , way. Just the chord of power.  Ambiguous, A Capitalist mode production.  Power is an end in itself. Seeking power to reform injustice is a contradiction in terms. For harmonious consensus all voices must strike a chord.    Oh such discordance felt heard seen  demanding resolution. Harmonies equal  in temperament to guide back home to the unity. One full revolution  Tracing the musical image in  Camra obscura, inverted and opposite, do you see what it is yet As the tonic marks a tranquil resting place so conformity leaves us resolved resiled and not reconciled Trapped  Power relations beget power relations, As the wheel of history turns repeating mistakes of previous revolutions.  As the wheel turns a revolution as a harmony resolves Resolution A new hub for human consciousness. Not the machine now but organic.  Yours to follow little people Know your place and praise Elite heroes, distant an shimmering As all mirages inspire the thirsty  to crawl into the oasis of illusion squeezing blood from exhausted humanity.   As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature.    The conversation has revolved and we find  Revolution plagiarized its past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and with your contribution dear reader a fourth part, harmonIsed. Or perhaps we as yet have to find a resolution , play on and seek new voices for our symphony of freedom is not yet written and least wise played freely with authentic joy.  Others we invite TO ,   Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irdHSmRrdh0</a> Cricket Appleseed  Published on 15 Apr 2016 Everything that was directly lived has receded into representation. Original File:</p>
<div class="embed-vimeo" style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/60328678" width="708" height="398" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IoUIHBSiVAY</a> The Society of the Spectacle by Guy Debord (1973) dub fr sub eng Augustine Joyce ublished on 7 Jan 2013 La Société du Spectacle (Society of the Spectacle) is a black and white 1973 film by the Situationist Guy Debord based on his 1967 book of the same title. It was Debord&#8217;s first feature-length film. It uses found footage and detournement in a radical criticism of mass marketing and its role in the alienation of modern society.   The 88 minute film took a year to make and incorporates footage from feature films, industrial films, news footage, advertisements, and still photographs.[1] The films include The Battleship Potemkin, October, Chapaev, The New Babylon, The Shanghai Gesture, For Whom the Bell Tolls, Rio Grande, They Died with Their Boots On, Johnny Guitar, and Mr. Arkadin, as well as other Soviet films.  A PDF form in tabulated format is available as the poem is concieved as a Matrix which can be read in columns as single voices or sequentiually as a dialogue. The PDF will be available for download for Patreon subscribers or customers on Amazon. The formatting for the downloads will be completed hopefully by the end of this weekend.         Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony.  Synthesis Speaks to introduce, And Thesis, Anti Thesis and Synthesis dialogue The conversation revolves and we find  Revolution plagiarizes past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and entreat your contribution dear reader for a fourth part, shall we harmonIse.  Synthesis.  Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature. ∲6/8 bb :  Thesis.  In a diary of a nobody, Mr Pooter, is everyman and woman. Striving. Petit Bourgeois, discordant with their lot, in earnest to impress.  Anti Thesis  Life liberty and the pursuit of happiness,  inalienable rights , the laws of Nature  and of natures god.A constitution  written for a usurping class, claiming  authority, a reflection of common sense,  and pained to see. This revolution of , by and for Whom? Synthesis. As the victor writes history so the powerful pass laws to satisfy their own ends. Power only represents the powerful.   Moyenne Bourgeoise and Grande Haute Bourgeoise. A Class cuisine, Escoffier Classical Aspiration. One acquires,  A bourgeoise aesthetic, Petit Bourgeoise Sycophancy.   Will the Chef of the constitution, Taste his own cooking. Does he as a class walk the walk and talk the talk Or is it ; do as I say and not as I do.  An appeal always made, at once  to Authority.Follow faithfully, blindly.  Ask they who would your bidding do. Listen to your life&#8217;s story, History, His History will not be yours? Be heard.   Pygmalion&#8217;s elocution for the ordinaire. Les rois et philosophes merde-et  ainsi de faire des dames. Conventional pieties of the extraordinaire, Elite.  Écoute Et Répète, Listen and repeat Learn by rote and do not question, To Each that has shall be given,  those who hath not will be punished, Know ones betters and issue scripted  speech when spoken too, Obsequious.  Do not blanche before appearance of grandeur. Pompous ceremony seeks to silence chafing curiosity.     How readily the pecking order has regiments in line , volunteers  to a false consciousness of liberation by  societies consumptive ills, Polysemous  At the sign, Obey and join the  que. Wait your turn and receive  your due. Punch the clock and Answer the bell. Ask not for whom the bell tolls, The bell rings the benefit makes a gift of what is rightfully yours.  The hand that gives also takes away. Often the gift merely returns that which was stolen from you.     Citizens within a polity, city state yet the peasants range free of sophistry  Freemen in the confined spaces offer conformity to the graduated mould.  Glamorous flashing city lights Suburbia within commute of higher Dreams. A stairway to real Estate heaven.The only Ladder, oh to be upon the bottom rung and rise.Dreams for mortgage, no hostage to Fortune.  Sophistication often masques ignorance. The humble and rustic often belies an appreciation of what truly is.     Calliopsis or Magnesia where poets slave to familiar rhymes and themes Not golden or silver words but workmanlike  fashion hymns of safe iron and copper.  On The city on the hill, Songs sung to green and pleasant lands My Country Right or wrong Patriotic duty, above the evidence heroic deeds, laurels earned Myths of Wagnerian operatic spectacle.  Behind the claimed reality of how things are lies a deeper truth clothed in the noble lie. He deceived by the noble lie is excluded as unworthy of an opinion.     Where Stockholm once commanded St-Petersberg in that peculiar syndrome did the people know of freedom, which noble lies  will accommodate the others&#8217;, too Slumber.  A common purpose, to ideals,Shared  and narrated from Cradle to grave. History written in our victorious mood Always times distant, always yesterday A better day , a past nostalgic searching For a future, yet to become tomorrow.  Being keen to please and seeking approval from authority feeds ego and starves the real self.  An irony of words pretending a meaning which no longer holds and yet serves to bind a convention, a grip that hampers the gait, Barre the pedestrian.  Witty Double entrendre to pacify, Laughing at the otherness, not of our own genre. Bending of wills or an ends of a means which makes  a meaner mind , setting examples Cruelty for kindness sake, who´s End?  The devil takes the hindmost. Trampling upon the unfortunate excuses elitist privilege. There but for the grace of privilege go they!     Self censored by a Mean temperament no longer just and a bespoke Key The city gates envelop to constrain Invention no longer a prize, only too fit.  Which mode of government befitting The cadence of Timocracy, Oligarchy or the tyranny of democracy, Which? A key to unlock the wealth of timbre Trusting in the chastity of greed the diabolas in musica. Descend below.  Discord or overbalance corrects naturally. In a system where gross imbalance and discord is evident are we to believe that harmony was ever thus.  As poets slave to the set rythym  so a ruling Class Slaves to support  its very tyranny, no purpose theirs, tis only to own be owned and Owe.  There is no Alternative, leave behind your utopian dreams of youth, Grown, reality demands that you sing Our  democratic song making it your own.  No third , way. Just the chord of power.  Ambiguous, A Capitalist mode production.  Power is an end in itself. Seeking power to reform injustice is a contradiction in terms. For harmonious consensus all voices must strike a chord.    Oh such discordance felt heard seen  demanding resolution. Harmonies equal  in temperament to guide back home to the unity. One full revolution  Tracing the musical image in  Camra obscura, inverted and opposite, do you see what it is yet As the tonic marks a tranquil resting place so conformity leaves us resolved resiled and not reconciled Trapped  Power relations beget power relations, As the wheel of history turns repeating mistakes of previous revolutions.  As the wheel turns a revolution as a harmony resolves Resolution A new hub for human consciousness. Not the machine now but organic.  Yours to follow little people Know your place and praise Elite heroes, distant an shimmering As all mirages inspire the thirsty  to crawl into the oasis of illusion squeezing blood from exhausted humanity.   As resolution of discord demands a return to the tonic. The Tonic for our dissonant condition is a harmonic resolution to the Chord of Nature.    The conversation has revolved and we find  Revolution plagiarized its past mistakes. In Consensus the three Voices resolve and with your contribution dear reader a fourth part, harmonIsed. Or perhaps we as yet have to find a resolution , play on and seek new voices for our symphony of freedom is not yet written and least wise played freely with authentic joy.  Others we invite TO ,   Start here with your own experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    <a href="http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html" rel="nofollow ugc">http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html</a> [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: This is not a rehearsal, this is an Orange. #Plandemic #The EgregorMatrixofIllusion.#COVIDPURPOSE THE OLIGARCHICAL VIRUS #PLATONOVIDVIRUS666 #ARISTOTOLILLIADOVIRUS33 #CRONYCAPITALISTVIRUS2020 A 9/11 EVENT.@WIKI_BALLOT @FINANCIALEYES #IABATO #SAM @JOEBLOB2		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-11082</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[This is not a rehearsal, this is an Orange. #Plandemic #The EgregorMatrixofIllusion.#COVIDPURPOSE THE OLIGARCHICAL VIRUS #PLATONOVIDVIRUS666 #ARISTOTOLILLIADOVIRUS33 #CRONYCAPITALISTVIRUS2020 A 9/11 EVENT.@WIKI_BALLOT @FINANCIALEYES #IABATO #SAM @JOEBLOB2]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-11082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] #MeetTheTechnocrats #The9comma9Percent #BourgoiseResolution      youtube.com/watch?v=HzpXRd…      youtube.com/watch?v=W-8hqL…            World Premiere Performance of Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmon&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] #MeetTheTechnocrats #The9comma9Percent #BourgoiseResolution      youtube.com/watch?v=HzpXRd…      youtube.com/watch?v=W-8hqL…            World Premiere Performance of Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmon&#8230; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Catch Up Democracy! PC is indifferent to outcomes. ‘Outcomes’ are regarded as having no autonomous reality, but are merely seen as part of abstract theory.´´ &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-5171</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Catch Up Democracy! PC is indifferent to outcomes. ‘Outcomes’ are regarded as having no autonomous reality, but are merely seen as part of abstract theory.´´ &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 05:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-5171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Roger Lewis https://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/&#8230;/world&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Roger Lewis https://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/&#8230;/world&#8230; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: GrubSt&#8217;Journal; Fags n Mags Accessibility, Paine &#38; Blake Sensibility #MOABS #GrubStreetJornal @JoeBlob20 @DavidGolemXIV @financialeyes &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-4535</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GrubSt&#8217;Journal; Fags n Mags Accessibility, Paine &#38; Blake Sensibility #MOABS #GrubStreetJornal @JoeBlob20 @DavidGolemXIV @financialeyes &#8211; Not The Grub Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 08:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-4535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] World Premiere Performance of Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmon&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] World Premiere Performance of Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmon&#8230; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Is the Green Party of England and Wales Liberal? &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-3049</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Is the Green Party of England and Wales Liberal? &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 07:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-3049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] WORLD PREMIERE PERFORMANCE OF BOURGEOIS RESOLUTION. A POEM IN THREE VOICES FOR ADDED 4TH PART HARMON&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] WORLD PREMIERE PERFORMANCE OF BOURGEOIS RESOLUTION. A POEM IN THREE VOICES FOR ADDED 4TH PART HARMON&#8230; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: At Times Like These. Epictetus or Wittgenstien. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-1630</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[At Times Like These. Epictetus or Wittgenstien. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 07:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-1630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/bourgeois-resolution-poem-in-three.html [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/bourgeois-resolution-poem-in-three.html" rel="nofollow ugc">http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/bourgeois-resolution-poem-in-three.html</a> [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-791</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bourgeois resolution. A poem in Three Voices for added 4th part Harmony. &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 05:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html       The PDF may be purchased to follow the Score of this poem at these [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] experience. Bring here your open mind and trust your instinctive feeling for truth. :D.S. ∲ ::    <a href="http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html" rel="nofollow ugc">http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/2016/09/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois.html</a>       The PDF may be purchased to follow the Score of this poem at these [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Shades of Grey; Netenyahu Zionism v kibbutzim קִבּוּצִים‬ / קיבוצים‬) &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-688</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shades of Grey; Netenyahu Zionism v kibbutzim קִבּוּצִים‬ / קיבוצים‬) &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/&#8230;/bourgeoi&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/&#8230;/bourgeoi&#038;#8230" rel="nofollow ugc">http://letthemconfectsweeterlies.blogspot.se/&#8230;/bourgeoi&#038;#8230</a>; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Information Technology		</title>
		<link>/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony/comment-page-1/#comment-54</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Information Technology]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 08:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2016/09/30/world-premiere-performance-of-bourgeois-resolution-a-poem-in-three-voices-for-added-4th-part-harmony#comment-54</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Your article is so nice. please visit my article too in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hanyoora.com/technology/replacement-samsung-note-7-phone-emits-smoke-on-u-s-plane-family.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Replacement Samsung Note 7 phone emits smoke on U.S. plane: family&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;:)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your article is so nice. please visit my article too in <a href="https://www.hanyoora.com/technology/replacement-samsung-note-7-phone-emits-smoke-on-u-s-plane-family.html" rel="nofollow">Replacement Samsung Note 7 phone emits smoke on U.S. plane: family</a><br />🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
