<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: #NovarraMedia #AaronBastani Strawmanning , shadow boxing and otherwise talking to himself. Cultural Marxism and the Art of appearing right.	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2019/04/23/novarramedia-aaronbastani-strawmanning-shadow-boxing-and-otherwise-talking-to-himself-cultural-marxism-and-the-art-of-appearing-right/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2019/04/23/novarramedia-aaronbastani-strawmanning-shadow-boxing-and-otherwise-talking-to-himself-cultural-marxism-and-the-art-of-appearing-right/</link>
	<description>Exegesis Hermeneutics Flux Capacitor of Truthiness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 05:53:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: rogerglewis		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/23/novarramedia-aaronbastani-strawmanning-shadow-boxing-and-otherwise-talking-to-himself-cultural-marxism-and-the-art-of-appearing-right/comment-page-1/#comment-3075</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rogerglewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 05:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4352#comment-3075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[http://kingwatch.co.nz/Christian_Political_Economy/jesus_and_economic_life.htm

The coming of the Roman Empire destroyed the community-based economy that God had provided for the children of Israel.

The Sadducees and the priestly families that collaborated with the Romans were rewarded with large land holdings. Many accumulated large blocks of land. The people who had previously owned them were turned into tenant farmers, who had to hand over at least half of their crops to their landlords.

The empire imposed exorbitant taxes on the ordinary people. This pushed most families into poverty. If taxes could not be paid, their property would be confiscated. The tax collectors got rich and the rest became tenant farmers or day labourers. Jesus saw the tax collectors as &quot;sick&quot; (Luke 5:31).

For ordinary people, storing up wealth was impossible. If the Roman soldiers found coins or grain hidden in a house, they would smash the house.

Debt was used to impoverish people and to steal their land. A person who was poor would be lent money at very high interest rates (50 percent) using their land as security. When they were unable to pay the interest or repay the loan, the interest would be added to the loan. In a few years, a small loan could grow to be worth more than the land given as security. The lender would demand the land to settle the debt.

Herod built a Greek-styled temple in Jerusalem. His son Antipas built the new Roman cities at Deopolis and Tiberius. The governor of Judea built a new city of Caesar Philip in honour of Caesar. To pay for these building projects, the people had to pay tribute.

People were hungry all the time.

During those days another large crowd gathered. Since they had nothing to eat, Jesus called his disciples to him and said, &quot;I have compassion for these people; they have already been with me three days and have nothing to eat. If I send them home hungry, they will collapse on the way (Mark 8:1-3).
The state of people&#039;s health was so bad that going without food was debilitating.

By Jesus time, most families in Israel had no land. Most of the land was controlled by a few powerful families and moneylenders. Tax collectors and soldiers would grab most of the crops that were grown and most money that was earned. The people were left with very little to live on. Most people were hungry most of the time. Many would have to find some work each day as a day labourer to buy their food for the day. That is why Jesus knew the people had followed him around the lake to listen to his teaching all day would be hungry. If they had not worked, they would have no food, and not be able to buy any.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kingwatch.co.nz/Christian_Political_Economy/jesus_and_economic_life.htm" rel="nofollow ugc">http://kingwatch.co.nz/Christian_Political_Economy/jesus_and_economic_life.htm</a></p>
<p>The coming of the Roman Empire destroyed the community-based economy that God had provided for the children of Israel.</p>
<p>The Sadducees and the priestly families that collaborated with the Romans were rewarded with large land holdings. Many accumulated large blocks of land. The people who had previously owned them were turned into tenant farmers, who had to hand over at least half of their crops to their landlords.</p>
<p>The empire imposed exorbitant taxes on the ordinary people. This pushed most families into poverty. If taxes could not be paid, their property would be confiscated. The tax collectors got rich and the rest became tenant farmers or day labourers. Jesus saw the tax collectors as &#8220;sick&#8221; (Luke 5:31).</p>
<p>For ordinary people, storing up wealth was impossible. If the Roman soldiers found coins or grain hidden in a house, they would smash the house.</p>
<p>Debt was used to impoverish people and to steal their land. A person who was poor would be lent money at very high interest rates (50 percent) using their land as security. When they were unable to pay the interest or repay the loan, the interest would be added to the loan. In a few years, a small loan could grow to be worth more than the land given as security. The lender would demand the land to settle the debt.</p>
<p>Herod built a Greek-styled temple in Jerusalem. His son Antipas built the new Roman cities at Deopolis and Tiberius. The governor of Judea built a new city of Caesar Philip in honour of Caesar. To pay for these building projects, the people had to pay tribute.</p>
<p>People were hungry all the time.</p>
<p>During those days another large crowd gathered. Since they had nothing to eat, Jesus called his disciples to him and said, &#8220;I have compassion for these people; they have already been with me three days and have nothing to eat. If I send them home hungry, they will collapse on the way (Mark 8:1-3).<br />
The state of people&#8217;s health was so bad that going without food was debilitating.</p>
<p>By Jesus time, most families in Israel had no land. Most of the land was controlled by a few powerful families and moneylenders. Tax collectors and soldiers would grab most of the crops that were grown and most money that was earned. The people were left with very little to live on. Most people were hungry most of the time. Many would have to find some work each day as a day labourer to buy their food for the day. That is why Jesus knew the people had followed him around the lake to listen to his teaching all day would be hungry. If they had not worked, they would have no food, and not be able to buy any.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
