<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Clowns to the left of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/</link>
	<description>Exegesis Hermeneutics Flux Capacitor of Truthiness</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:57:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: rogerglewis		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-4014</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rogerglewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:57:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-4014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry for the typos in my previous post. Just to wrap up here as I do not wish to just argue with myself. I had a discussion back in April With the Author and another of his Followers of a 3 part blog post on Watts Up with That. The title of the Posts was as Follows. Peak Oil, Abiotic Oil &#038; EROEI: Real(ish) Things That Don’t Matter, Part One: Peak Oil David Middleton / April 22, 2019 https://wattsupwiththat.com/2019/04/22/peak-oil-abiotic-oil-eroei-realish-things-that-dont-matter/ EROEI &quot;EROEI is the preferred energy metric for Malthusians, environmental activists, Warmunists and proponents of uneconomic energy sources. Invention of this concept is generally credited to an ecology professor…&quot; Will give you a flavour, this wing of the Climate debate is I think as useful to the Political project of CO2 Carbon Trading as the Catastrophist Wing, both are fueled by, Polemic, Rhetoric and Emotional bed wetting and dummy spitting Its a Manichean thing and this Roger Pelke Junior Talk at the GWPF is worth watching on that point regarding the Polarised debate and Religous fervour pursued on both sides, parading their Hurt Feelings and needing to repair to their various Churches or Cult HQ,s A bracket into which I would place the Perspectiva, project of Rowson. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iene_nipRXM I took David Middleton to Task on his Appeals to the Rhetoric and Ad Hominem rather than tackling the substantive issues of Energy-based metrics for Energy investment and Consumption Decisions. &quot;The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters- Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half-cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions. Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again- https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/ &quot;Clowns to the left of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/ The Author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The Debate about climate. Economics and Political Economy are imprecise pseudo-scientific priesthoods every bit as manufactured and absurd as Micheal Mann and his desperado band of cultist cool-aid hawkers. Steelers Wheel sums it up really. Quite one of the worse articles I have read here. &quot; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofs_GyQXJ9k https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/ The Exchanges in the discussion are pated into the comments of my own blog pointing at the David Middleton series of articles, the 3 articles and all the comments are worth reading David is a very Knowledgable Oil Industry Engineer, The point regarding the Role of Debt-based money in the Late Stage Financialised State monopoly Capitalism under which most people are net losers and a vanishingly small percentage are net Gainers, is hard to see There is a very real sense of Peak Ignorance around the current Hiatus we face as the Paradigm shift takes place. The Shift To what is the question? ultimately ending on a Philosophical note the argument boils down to Determinism or Free Will and Herecletus or Parmenides. As a Pelagian and a religious man myself, I do not need Rowson&#039;s ethical code to point me in the direction of the Cult of #WrongKindofGreen I stand with Liberty, Free will and bow to no man, https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/06/18/it-is-who-you-know-and-what-you-believe-that-counts-the-semi-establishment-pelagianism-of-bremain-brexit-brino-dominiccummings-cynics-saw-what-people-could-be-and-were-angered-by-what-they-h/ https://youtu.be/qNjmPyHIoOc]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the typos in my previous post. Just to wrap up here as I do not wish to just argue with myself. I had a discussion back in April With the Author and another of his Followers of a 3 part blog post on Watts Up with That. The title of the Posts was as Follows. Peak Oil, Abiotic Oil &amp; EROEI: Real(ish) Things That Don’t Matter, Part One: Peak Oil David Middleton / April 22, 2019 <a href="https://wattsupwiththat.com/2019/04/22/peak-oil-abiotic-oil-eroei-realish-things-that-dont-matter/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://wattsupwiththat.com/2019/04/22/peak-oil-abiotic-oil-eroei-realish-things-that-dont-matter/</a> EROEI &#8220;EROEI is the preferred energy metric for Malthusians, environmental activists, Warmunists and proponents of uneconomic energy sources. Invention of this concept is generally credited to an ecology professor…&#8221; Will give you a flavour, this wing of the Climate debate is I think as useful to the Political project of CO2 Carbon Trading as the Catastrophist Wing, both are fueled by, Polemic, Rhetoric and Emotional bed wetting and dummy spitting Its a Manichean thing and this Roger Pelke Junior Talk at the GWPF is worth watching on that point regarding the Polarised debate and Religous fervour pursued on both sides, parading their Hurt Feelings and needing to repair to their various Churches or Cult HQ,s A bracket into which I would place the Perspectiva, project of Rowson. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iene_nipRXM" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iene_nipRXM</a> I took David Middleton to Task on his Appeals to the Rhetoric and Ad Hominem rather than tackling the substantive issues of Energy-based metrics for Energy investment and Consumption Decisions. &#8220;The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters- Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half-cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions. Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again- <a href="https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/</a> &#8220;Clowns to the left of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/</a> The Author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The Debate about climate. Economics and Political Economy are imprecise pseudo-scientific priesthoods every bit as manufactured and absurd as Micheal Mann and his desperado band of cultist cool-aid hawkers. Steelers Wheel sums it up really. Quite one of the worse articles I have read here. &#8221; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofs_GyQXJ9k" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofs_GyQXJ9k</a> <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/</a> The Exchanges in the discussion are pated into the comments of my own blog pointing at the David Middleton series of articles, the 3 articles and all the comments are worth reading David is a very Knowledgable Oil Industry Engineer, The point regarding the Role of Debt-based money in the Late Stage Financialised State monopoly Capitalism under which most people are net losers and a vanishingly small percentage are net Gainers, is hard to see There is a very real sense of Peak Ignorance around the current Hiatus we face as the Paradigm shift takes place. The Shift To what is the question? ultimately ending on a Philosophical note the argument boils down to Determinism or Free Will and Herecletus or Parmenides. As a Pelagian and a religious man myself, I do not need Rowson&#8217;s ethical code to point me in the direction of the Cult of #WrongKindofGreen I stand with Liberty, Free will and bow to no man, <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/06/18/it-is-who-you-know-and-what-you-believe-that-counts-the-semi-establishment-pelagianism-of-bremain-brexit-brino-dominiccummings-cynics-saw-what-people-could-be-and-were-angered-by-what-they-h/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/06/18/it-is-who-you-know-and-what-you-believe-that-counts-the-semi-establishment-pelagianism-of-bremain-brexit-brino-dominiccummings-cynics-saw-what-people-could-be-and-were-angered-by-what-they-h/</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/qNjmPyHIoOc" rel="nofollow ugc">https://youtu.be/qNjmPyHIoOc</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: #153. One for the sceptics. Free Will or Determinism , The Climate Religion Rowsons #Perspectiva &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-4011</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[#153. One for the sceptics. Free Will or Determinism , The Climate Religion Rowsons #Perspectiva &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-4011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#8230; The Author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The Debate [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230</a>; The Author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The Debate [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: rogerglewis		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-4010</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rogerglewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-4010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 8:33 am
There is a fission reactor design that is as cheap as coal to build, that does not have catastrophic failure modes, that is six times more fuel efficient, that can be mass produced, that was built and tested 50 years ago…..

Great, show me one in commercial operation so I can validate that your assertions are true in reality. Oh wait, what’s that you say? there *isn’t* any in commercial operation? Then, sorry, you are blowing smoke. All you’ve said is hype about vapor ware. Get back to us when you have one (just one, that’s not too much to ask is it?) in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to reality.

bonbon  April 25, 2019 at 9:34 am
The Royal Society’s Newton said to Frenchman Papin’s Proposition, that a steam engine would cost too much, in 1707. Nothing happened until Benjamin Franklin intervened with Watt decades later. Papin was disappeared.

Since then Britain has lost control of technology, and now China is simply ignoring the Newtons of to today. The Royal Mint’s Newton would likely have praised wind generators “cheapness”.

William Astley  April 25, 2019 at 10:02 am
What is your point?

That politicians are miss informed? There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago.

That the nuclear ‘industry’ is fixed where breakthroughs sit around (are hidden from the public) for 50 years. That it is obvious that the Department of Energy is not interested in a ‘breakthrough’ fission reactor design.

Duh. Is CAGW a real worry or not? Are the cult of CAGW interested in a solution that will cost effectively reduce CO2 emissions.

Why are we spending trillions of dollars on green stuff that does not work to reduce CO2 emissions, when there is a fission reactor design that is six times more fuel efficient, that does not have catastrophic failure modes, and so on?

Terrestrial Energy has a molten salt reactor that has reached Canada regulator phase 2 approval.

Terrestrial Energy

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OgTgV3Kq49U

https://www.technologyreview.com/s/609194/advanced-nuclear-finds-a-more-welcome-home-in-canada/

Terrestrial Energy unveils SMR licensing plans

Terrestrial included the status of the design, analyses, testing, licensing, and project planning for its Integral Molten Salt Reactor (IMSR), which is a liquid-fuelled, high-temperature, 400 MWt advanced reactor power plant design.

Terrestrial is examining four sites for its first commercial plant, which include the Idaho National Laboratory (INL) and additional sites east of the Mississippi River.

Last year, New York-headquartered Terrestrial Energy USA’s parent, Canada’s Terrestrial Energy Inc, announced its plans to engage with the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission in a pre-licensing design review, a first step towards an eventual licence application.

John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 10:30 am
The point is: You are making a lot of statements of fact that are not facts because what you are shilling doesn’t actually exist in commercial operation where such “facts” would be verified. Stop hyping the vapor ware as if it really existed in reality. MSR sounds good on paper, I’d love to see it live up to the hype but all we have so far is the hype. that’s it. Get back to us when you can show one in commercial operation. One should not be too much to ask for something that you endlessly talk about as if it’s ready to go into operation at the flip of a switch.

John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 10:36 am
There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago.

And yet you spout a lot of “facts” about something that you admit has no official documentation and still is not in commercial operation many decades after those tests. Like a said, lots of hype little in the way of real world validation.

William Astley  April 25, 2019 at 10:55 am
John,

The official documentation of the test was found.

The test was a complete success. There are no significant technical issues with building the no water, no fuel rod, no catastrophic failure mode design tomorrow.

The NASA engineer meet with some of the retired engineers and scientists that worked on the test. They all said it was successful and they did not understand why the cheap as coal, no failure mode reactor design is not used today.

There has a PBS nuclear special that discussed the test and had film coverage of the meeting of the NASA engineer and the original test workers.

The problem is we are installing green stuff that does not work when there is a real solution that does work.

John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 11:43 am
William you said “There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago” now you say “The official documentation of the test was found” those two sentences contradict each other. Pick one story and stick to it please.

The test was a complete success. There are no significant technical issues with building the no water, no fuel rod, no catastrophic failure mode design tomorrow.

Great, then you should have no problems showing me one (just one, that’s all I ask) in commercial operation. Eh? what’s that? there aren’t *ANY* in commercial operation? Then you are once again pushing hype not reality.

The NASA engineer meet with some of the retired engineers and scientists that worked on the test….

blah, blah, blah. Enough hype, show me the reality in commercial operation.

The problem is we are installing green stuff that does not work when there is a real solution that does work.

You are half right. We are installing unreliable green stuff, but the “real solution” you keep pushing is vapor ware until you can show just one in commercial operation. And you can’t, because there are none in commercial operation. So stop lying about how great and power your vapor ware is. Seeing is believing and you have nothing to see. Only when you have something to show (one, just one will do, in commercial operation) then and only then can you say how great and wonderful they are because then and only then can everyone see how the hype stands up to the reality.

Roger Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 5:38 am
https://www.bitchute.com/video/2mMsqFAIdsE/ This is in french there is an abridged English language version on YouTube then there is this.

http://euanmearns.com/thorcon-molten-salt-fission-power-plant/

http://euanmearns.com/the-uks-small-modular-reactor-competition/



Roger Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 6:00 am
https://topdocumentaryfilms.com/thorium-nasa/ This is a 6-hour Thorium Reactor video,

John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 6:51 am
Roger your links suffer the same problem as William’s posts: all hype, no actual commercially operating reactors to look at. Lot’s of “plans” and “projects” but still no actual commercially operating reactors. Get back to us when you have one (just one, that’s really, really not too much to ask) that is online and in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to the reality.

Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:26 am
Actually John the Indonesian Trial RIg is I believe in Testing and of cource Weinbergs Rig worked perfectly well back in the late 60’s and ran successfully for several years.

The dISCUSSION ON eUAN mEANS SITE IS VERY INTERESTING WHERE SOME CONVENTIONAL nUCLEAR ENGINEERS QUESTION THE LOW-LEVEL WASTE TREATMENT ( sorry caps came on pushed for time so leaving)

http://thorconpower.com/project/

So actually it seems very promising the other area of interesting is battery storage at a large scale this Project is fascinating in that regard.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sddb0Khx0yA

2012 ted talk and the commercialisation
https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/german-firm-turns-aluminum-smelter-into-huge-battery

rogerglewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:29 am


Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:47 am
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tyDbq5HRs0o
Original Public Info film from Oakridge Laboratory

John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 10:27 am
Actually John the Indonesian Trial RIg is I believe in Testing and of cource Weinbergs Rig worked perfectly well back in the late 60’s and ran successfully for several years.

Roger, Testing and actual commercial operation are *two different things*. There are many, many products that have made it to the testing phase that never progress beyond to become commercial (case in point the 1960s tests you speak of never resulted in a commercially operating reactor). Testing is, in part, where you learn if the product is viable enough to attempt commercial application. So again, get back to us when you have one (Just One, that’s all that is being asked of you, that shouldn’t be too much to ask if it’s everything the hype you’ve been shoveling is to be believed) in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to actual operating reality.

Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 10:55 am
John,
The Chinese are going ahead with this technology as are the French and the Indonesians are also looking at having commercially operating Thorncon plants working by 2022. Oakridge produced Electricity for several years the reason the project was not commercialised is simply to do with by-products suitable for weapons use, Thorium does not have that by-product and its really that simple.
Thorium offers cheap and abundant Electricity which would change the Energy sectors Scarcity based model quite a lot that is also an objection to it from the Oil and Gas sector.
Here are Dr Tim Morgans Dangerous Exponentials and Perfect Storm reports. They bear watching Even the Oil and Gas industry are not immune from the Exponential function and for prosperity to grow so too does surplus available energy have to grow.

https://surplusenergyeconomics.wordpress.com/resources/
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2016/11/21/climate-change-agw-and-all-points-from-activism-to-skepticism/
A section on my PDF on Climate science.
https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B6ZHfkDjveZzYXU3UHhLem1HQms/view
reproduces Bob parkers excellent article on the Petro Dollar whys and wherefores.
http://priceofoil.org/content/uploads/2011/01/DrillingIntoDebt.pdf

Robert Parker, CEO of Holborn Assets in Dubai
Answered Sep 17, 2016
Originally Answered: Why is oil priced in US dollars?
Well, in order to understand it, you can read this article that is available on Holborn Assets official website: Why is the US Dollar Still the Reserve Currency of the World

In this article you will find out:

why the USD has the world currency status?
what was the Nixon shock and why it happened?
how the USD got to the petrodollar system?
what is the main oil producer that collaborates with the US?
You will discover that the USD gave up the gold standard and tried to replace the gold with oil, so they made a deal with the Saudi Arabia, and later with other OPEC countries, to sell their oil exclusively in exchange for the USD. In this way, the USD demand was maintained and the US currency is still the world reserve currency today.

Happy reading!

Regards,

Bob Parker

Holborn Assets About Us

715 views · View Upvoters · Answer may need improvement

Roger Lewis

Recommended
All
Robert Parker, CEO of Holborn Assets in Dubai
Answered Sep 17, 2016
It all goes back to the Bretton Woods agreement, when the USD was selected (imposed) as a world reserve currency. It was right after the WW2 was almost done, and the pound had the status at that time.

https://holbornassets.com/blog/finance/us-dollar-still-the-reserve-currency-of-the-world/

John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 10:32 am
So actually it seems very promising

Lots of proposed products that never make it commercially looked very promising at one time or another. Promising, however, doesn’t equate to being commercially viable. I’d love to see MSR live up to it’s hype but it hasn’t managed in yet in 50s years. which makes all these pronouncements by some about how it’s “the future or energy” that’s “ready to start tomorrow” so much hot air. I’ll believe it when I see it, and until there a commercial reactor (which there currently isn’t) there’s nothing to see here at this time.

John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 11:45 am
the Indonesians are also looking at having commercially operating Thorncon plants working by 2022

Great then get back to us in 2022 and we can see how well it worked out (or if it’s still “a couple of years away”) – anything before then is just more blowing the hype smoke about vaporware.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 8:33 am<br />
There is a fission reactor design that is as cheap as coal to build, that does not have catastrophic failure modes, that is six times more fuel efficient, that can be mass produced, that was built and tested 50 years ago…..</p>
<p>Great, show me one in commercial operation so I can validate that your assertions are true in reality. Oh wait, what’s that you say? there *isn’t* any in commercial operation? Then, sorry, you are blowing smoke. All you’ve said is hype about vapor ware. Get back to us when you have one (just one, that’s not too much to ask is it?) in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to reality.</p>
<p>bonbon  April 25, 2019 at 9:34 am<br />
The Royal Society’s Newton said to Frenchman Papin’s Proposition, that a steam engine would cost too much, in 1707. Nothing happened until Benjamin Franklin intervened with Watt decades later. Papin was disappeared.</p>
<p>Since then Britain has lost control of technology, and now China is simply ignoring the Newtons of to today. The Royal Mint’s Newton would likely have praised wind generators “cheapness”.</p>
<p>William Astley  April 25, 2019 at 10:02 am<br />
What is your point?</p>
<p>That politicians are miss informed? There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago.</p>
<p>That the nuclear ‘industry’ is fixed where breakthroughs sit around (are hidden from the public) for 50 years. That it is obvious that the Department of Energy is not interested in a ‘breakthrough’ fission reactor design.</p>
<p>Duh. Is CAGW a real worry or not? Are the cult of CAGW interested in a solution that will cost effectively reduce CO2 emissions.</p>
<p>Why are we spending trillions of dollars on green stuff that does not work to reduce CO2 emissions, when there is a fission reactor design that is six times more fuel efficient, that does not have catastrophic failure modes, and so on?</p>
<p>Terrestrial Energy has a molten salt reactor that has reached Canada regulator phase 2 approval.</p>
<p>Terrestrial Energy</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OgTgV3Kq49U" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OgTgV3Kq49U</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/609194/advanced-nuclear-finds-a-more-welcome-home-in-canada/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.technologyreview.com/s/609194/advanced-nuclear-finds-a-more-welcome-home-in-canada/</a></p>
<p>Terrestrial Energy unveils SMR licensing plans</p>
<p>Terrestrial included the status of the design, analyses, testing, licensing, and project planning for its Integral Molten Salt Reactor (IMSR), which is a liquid-fuelled, high-temperature, 400 MWt advanced reactor power plant design.</p>
<p>Terrestrial is examining four sites for its first commercial plant, which include the Idaho National Laboratory (INL) and additional sites east of the Mississippi River.</p>
<p>Last year, New York-headquartered Terrestrial Energy USA’s parent, Canada’s Terrestrial Energy Inc, announced its plans to engage with the Canadian Nuclear Safety Commission in a pre-licensing design review, a first step towards an eventual licence application.</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 10:30 am<br />
The point is: You are making a lot of statements of fact that are not facts because what you are shilling doesn’t actually exist in commercial operation where such “facts” would be verified. Stop hyping the vapor ware as if it really existed in reality. MSR sounds good on paper, I’d love to see it live up to the hype but all we have so far is the hype. that’s it. Get back to us when you can show one in commercial operation. One should not be too much to ask for something that you endlessly talk about as if it’s ready to go into operation at the flip of a switch.</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 10:36 am<br />
There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago.</p>
<p>And yet you spout a lot of “facts” about something that you admit has no official documentation and still is not in commercial operation many decades after those tests. Like a said, lots of hype little in the way of real world validation.</p>
<p>William Astley  April 25, 2019 at 10:55 am<br />
John,</p>
<p>The official documentation of the test was found.</p>
<p>The test was a complete success. There are no significant technical issues with building the no water, no fuel rod, no catastrophic failure mode design tomorrow.</p>
<p>The NASA engineer meet with some of the retired engineers and scientists that worked on the test. They all said it was successful and they did not understand why the cheap as coal, no failure mode reactor design is not used today.</p>
<p>There has a PBS nuclear special that discussed the test and had film coverage of the meeting of the NASA engineer and the original test workers.</p>
<p>The problem is we are installing green stuff that does not work when there is a real solution that does work.</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 11:43 am<br />
William you said “There is no official documentation summarizing the reactor test 50 years ago” now you say “The official documentation of the test was found” those two sentences contradict each other. Pick one story and stick to it please.</p>
<p>The test was a complete success. There are no significant technical issues with building the no water, no fuel rod, no catastrophic failure mode design tomorrow.</p>
<p>Great, then you should have no problems showing me one (just one, that’s all I ask) in commercial operation. Eh? what’s that? there aren’t *ANY* in commercial operation? Then you are once again pushing hype not reality.</p>
<p>The NASA engineer meet with some of the retired engineers and scientists that worked on the test….</p>
<p>blah, blah, blah. Enough hype, show me the reality in commercial operation.</p>
<p>The problem is we are installing green stuff that does not work when there is a real solution that does work.</p>
<p>You are half right. We are installing unreliable green stuff, but the “real solution” you keep pushing is vapor ware until you can show just one in commercial operation. And you can’t, because there are none in commercial operation. So stop lying about how great and power your vapor ware is. Seeing is believing and you have nothing to see. Only when you have something to show (one, just one will do, in commercial operation) then and only then can you say how great and wonderful they are because then and only then can everyone see how the hype stands up to the reality.</p>
<p>Roger Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 5:38 am<br />
<a href="https://www.bitchute.com/video/2mMsqFAIdsE/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.bitchute.com/video/2mMsqFAIdsE/</a> This is in french there is an abridged English language version on YouTube then there is this.</p>
<p><a href="http://euanmearns.com/thorcon-molten-salt-fission-power-plant/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://euanmearns.com/thorcon-molten-salt-fission-power-plant/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://euanmearns.com/the-uks-small-modular-reactor-competition/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://euanmearns.com/the-uks-small-modular-reactor-competition/</a></p>
<p>Roger Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 6:00 am<br />
<a href="https://topdocumentaryfilms.com/thorium-nasa/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://topdocumentaryfilms.com/thorium-nasa/</a> This is a 6-hour Thorium Reactor video,</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 6:51 am<br />
Roger your links suffer the same problem as William’s posts: all hype, no actual commercially operating reactors to look at. Lot’s of “plans” and “projects” but still no actual commercially operating reactors. Get back to us when you have one (just one, that’s really, really not too much to ask) that is online and in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to the reality.</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:26 am<br />
Actually John the Indonesian Trial RIg is I believe in Testing and of cource Weinbergs Rig worked perfectly well back in the late 60’s and ran successfully for several years.</p>
<p>The dISCUSSION ON eUAN mEANS SITE IS VERY INTERESTING WHERE SOME CONVENTIONAL nUCLEAR ENGINEERS QUESTION THE LOW-LEVEL WASTE TREATMENT ( sorry caps came on pushed for time so leaving)</p>
<p><a href="http://thorconpower.com/project/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://thorconpower.com/project/</a></p>
<p>So actually it seems very promising the other area of interesting is battery storage at a large scale this Project is fascinating in that regard.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sddb0Khx0yA" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sddb0Khx0yA</a></p>
<p>2012 ted talk and the commercialisation<br />
<a href="https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/german-firm-turns-aluminum-smelter-into-huge-battery" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/german-firm-turns-aluminum-smelter-into-huge-battery</a></p>
<p>rogerglewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:29 am</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 9:47 am<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tyDbq5HRs0o" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tyDbq5HRs0o</a><br />
Original Public Info film from Oakridge Laboratory</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 10:27 am<br />
Actually John the Indonesian Trial RIg is I believe in Testing and of cource Weinbergs Rig worked perfectly well back in the late 60’s and ran successfully for several years.</p>
<p>Roger, Testing and actual commercial operation are *two different things*. There are many, many products that have made it to the testing phase that never progress beyond to become commercial (case in point the 1960s tests you speak of never resulted in a commercially operating reactor). Testing is, in part, where you learn if the product is viable enough to attempt commercial application. So again, get back to us when you have one (Just One, that’s all that is being asked of you, that shouldn’t be too much to ask if it’s everything the hype you’ve been shoveling is to be believed) in commercial operation so that the hype can be compared to actual operating reality.</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 26, 2019 at 10:55 am<br />
John,<br />
The Chinese are going ahead with this technology as are the French and the Indonesians are also looking at having commercially operating Thorncon plants working by 2022. Oakridge produced Electricity for several years the reason the project was not commercialised is simply to do with by-products suitable for weapons use, Thorium does not have that by-product and its really that simple.<br />
Thorium offers cheap and abundant Electricity which would change the Energy sectors Scarcity based model quite a lot that is also an objection to it from the Oil and Gas sector.<br />
Here are Dr Tim Morgans Dangerous Exponentials and Perfect Storm reports. They bear watching Even the Oil and Gas industry are not immune from the Exponential function and for prosperity to grow so too does surplus available energy have to grow.</p>
<p><a href="https://surplusenergyeconomics.wordpress.com/resources/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://surplusenergyeconomics.wordpress.com/resources/</a><br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2016/11/21/climate-change-agw-and-all-points-from-activism-to-skepticism/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2016/11/21/climate-change-agw-and-all-points-from-activism-to-skepticism/</a><br />
A section on my PDF on Climate science.<br />
<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B6ZHfkDjveZzYXU3UHhLem1HQms/view" rel="nofollow ugc">https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B6ZHfkDjveZzYXU3UHhLem1HQms/view</a><br />
reproduces Bob parkers excellent article on the Petro Dollar whys and wherefores.<br />
<a href="http://priceofoil.org/content/uploads/2011/01/DrillingIntoDebt.pdf" rel="nofollow ugc">http://priceofoil.org/content/uploads/2011/01/DrillingIntoDebt.pdf</a></p>
<p>Robert Parker, CEO of Holborn Assets in Dubai<br />
Answered Sep 17, 2016<br />
Originally Answered: Why is oil priced in US dollars?<br />
Well, in order to understand it, you can read this article that is available on Holborn Assets official website: Why is the US Dollar Still the Reserve Currency of the World</p>
<p>In this article you will find out:</p>
<p>why the USD has the world currency status?<br />
what was the Nixon shock and why it happened?<br />
how the USD got to the petrodollar system?<br />
what is the main oil producer that collaborates with the US?<br />
You will discover that the USD gave up the gold standard and tried to replace the gold with oil, so they made a deal with the Saudi Arabia, and later with other OPEC countries, to sell their oil exclusively in exchange for the USD. In this way, the USD demand was maintained and the US currency is still the world reserve currency today.</p>
<p>Happy reading!</p>
<p>Regards,</p>
<p>Bob Parker</p>
<p>Holborn Assets About Us</p>
<p>715 views · View Upvoters · Answer may need improvement</p>
<p>Roger Lewis</p>
<p>Recommended<br />
All<br />
Robert Parker, CEO of Holborn Assets in Dubai<br />
Answered Sep 17, 2016<br />
It all goes back to the Bretton Woods agreement, when the USD was selected (imposed) as a world reserve currency. It was right after the WW2 was almost done, and the pound had the status at that time.</p>
<p><a href="https://holbornassets.com/blog/finance/us-dollar-still-the-reserve-currency-of-the-world/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://holbornassets.com/blog/finance/us-dollar-still-the-reserve-currency-of-the-world/</a></p>
<p>John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 10:32 am<br />
So actually it seems very promising</p>
<p>Lots of proposed products that never make it commercially looked very promising at one time or another. Promising, however, doesn’t equate to being commercially viable. I’d love to see MSR live up to it’s hype but it hasn’t managed in yet in 50s years. which makes all these pronouncements by some about how it’s “the future or energy” that’s “ready to start tomorrow” so much hot air. I’ll believe it when I see it, and until there a commercial reactor (which there currently isn’t) there’s nothing to see here at this time.</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 26, 2019 at 11:45 am<br />
the Indonesians are also looking at having commercially operating Thorncon plants working by 2022</p>
<p>Great then get back to us in 2022 and we can see how well it worked out (or if it’s still “a couple of years away”) – anything before then is just more blowing the hype smoke about vaporware.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: rogerglewis		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-4009</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rogerglewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-4009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roger  April 24, 2019 at 8:53 pm
Clowns to the left of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/

The author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The &quot;Debate&quot; about climate.

Economics and Political Economy are imprecise pseudo-scientific priesthoods every bit as manufactured and absurd as Micheal Mann and his desperado band of cultist cool-aid hawkers.

Steelers Wheel sums it up really. QUite one of the worse articles I have read here.



Joel O&#039;Bryan  April 24, 2019 at 9:19 pm
Roger,
Your post has the same level of intellectual depth as an AO-C interview on US fiscal policy.
(Cue the Dean Wormer video-snippet.)

Roger G Lewis  April 24, 2019 at 10:34 pm
Joel O’Bryan April 24, 2019 at 9:19 pm
See above, Joel, I am happy to engage in Argument.
Roger April 24, 2019 at 8:38 pm
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/ The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit
basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters-
Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions.
Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again-
https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/

Roger G Lewis Your comment is awaiting moderation.
April 24, 2019 at 10:27 pm
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/28/the-ngo-sock-puppet-complex-watts-up-with-that-useful-idiot-of-big-finance-donteatyellowsnow-wrongkindofgreen-conquestofdough/

David ( Mr, Dr, Prof?) Middleton.
GDP itself is a fundamentally unsound metric based as it is even when Inflation Adjusted a purely subjective unit of Account. The question is not one of Political Economy but simple Metrology that is the Science of measuring things.

Lazards produce an excellent report on the levelised cost of Electriciity and Energy production and Dr Tim Morgan, (ex-head of research at Tullett Prebon ( not exactly a bunch of Green Hippy Commies) with his SEEDS energy Database look at surplus energy prodcution and its correlation to prosperity.
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/25/energy-economy-renewables-including-nuclear/

Energy Cost of Energy is explained here by Dr Tim Morgan.

“SEEDS uses an alternative measure, ECoE (the Energy Cost of Energy), which expresses cost as a percentage of the gross energy accessed. Because the world economy is a closed system, ECoE is not directly analogous to ‘cost’ in the usual financial sense. Rather, it is an economic rent, limiting the choice we exercise over any given quantity of energy. If we have 100 units of energy, and the ECoE is 5%, we exercise choice (or ‘discretion’) over 95 units. If ECoE rises to 10%, we now have discretion over only 90 units, even though the gross amount remains 100.This is loosely analogous to personal prosperity. If someone’s income remains the same, but the cost of essentials rises, that person is worse off, even though income itself hasn’t changed”.

Understanding ECoEECoE evolves over time. In the early stages of any given resource, ECoE is driven downwards by geographic reach, and by economies of scale. Once maturity is reached, depletion takes over as the driver, pushing ECoE upwards.
In the pre-maturity phase, technology accelerates the fall in ECoE driven by reach and scale. Post-maturity, technology acts to mitigate the rise caused by depletion. But – and this is often misunderstood – the capabilities of technology are limited to the envelope of the physical characteristics of the resource.
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/redefining-fiscal-conservatism-the-terra-energy-based-fiscal-unit-fores-and-lagom-white-paper-boundary-conditions-for-a-fiscal-conservatism-based-upon-circular-economics-part-one-scope/

WIth FIAT currencies and floating exchange rates, any money based measure that does not have a properly defined referent is sufficient to render any further analysis using it as its basis at best unreliable but in fact worse than useless, corrupted in every sense of the word in fact.

https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/

I look forward to a fruitful Discussion perhaps you will be good enough to expand upon your Critique? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />

beng135  April 25, 2019 at 7:00 am
Roger, what in the world are you yapping about? AOC has it all over you.

Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 11:44 am
beng135, Yapping? I suspect what you are describing fits rater better your short snappy interjection. My own Long Winded efforts may be boring, tedious and ultimately nonsense but Yapping They are not.
Heres the Multi-Media Web Site for my Novel Conquest of Dough,

https://theconquestofdough.weebly.com/the-conquest-of-dough.html

John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 12:36 pm
My own Long Winded efforts may be boring, tedious and ultimately nonsense

Well, at least you have some self-awareness. Kudos for that. (though I don’t think there’s any “may” about it).

Phoenix44  April 25, 2019 at 7:49 am
FIAT currencies – which are actually fiat currencies BTW – BAD BAD BAD.

There we go, shortened your rantings.

A price captures what you need to know – what people are willing to pay for something. A unit of energy does not. Ergo, a unit of energy is a dumb way of working out whether people are doing the right thing economically. I would trade a vast amount of oil for a bottle of water if I was stranded in a desert by a big oil-field, and vice versa if stranded in the desert with a taker full of water and out of petrol.

John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 9:57 am
Succinctly put and much more coherent that the long form rantings it shortened. Thanks Pheonix44.

Paul  April 25, 2019 at 1:12 pm
Try paying the IRS with non fiat money

Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 9:01 pm
You miss the point completely.
A FIAT Currency is absolutely fine what the problem is is the USe of the Fiat currency where the unit of account is not well defined. All Fiat currencies are at present ill-defined rendering all objective pricing and valuation meaningless to the point of absurdity.

See Wes Freeberg #Quanta
https://twitter.com/i/moments/938457795816579084

roger lewis  April 25, 2019 at 9:29 pm
https://twitter.com/wesfree/status/938560790117998592 do look at the full link but this is a bumper sticker]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Roger  April 24, 2019 at 8:53 pm<br />
Clowns to the left of me Jokers to the Right. Useful idiots for usury everywhere. Watts up With That #LimitstoNouse<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/</a></p>
<p>The author lets us all down that insist that empirical evidence must be respected in The &#8220;Debate&#8221; about climate.</p>
<p>Economics and Political Economy are imprecise pseudo-scientific priesthoods every bit as manufactured and absurd as Micheal Mann and his desperado band of cultist cool-aid hawkers.</p>
<p>Steelers Wheel sums it up really. QUite one of the worse articles I have read here.</p>
<p>Joel O&#8217;Bryan  April 24, 2019 at 9:19 pm<br />
Roger,<br />
Your post has the same level of intellectual depth as an AO-C interview on US fiscal policy.<br />
(Cue the Dean Wormer video-snippet.)</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 24, 2019 at 10:34 pm<br />
Joel O’Bryan April 24, 2019 at 9:19 pm<br />
See above, Joel, I am happy to engage in Argument.<br />
Roger April 24, 2019 at 8:38 pm<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/</a> The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit<br />
basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters-<br />
Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions.<br />
Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again-<br />
<a href="https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/</a></p>
<p>Roger G Lewis Your comment is awaiting moderation.<br />
April 24, 2019 at 10:27 pm<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/28/the-ngo-sock-puppet-complex-watts-up-with-that-useful-idiot-of-big-finance-donteatyellowsnow-wrongkindofgreen-conquestofdough/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/28/the-ngo-sock-puppet-complex-watts-up-with-that-useful-idiot-of-big-finance-donteatyellowsnow-wrongkindofgreen-conquestofdough/</a></p>
<p>David ( Mr, Dr, Prof?) Middleton.<br />
GDP itself is a fundamentally unsound metric based as it is even when Inflation Adjusted a purely subjective unit of Account. The question is not one of Political Economy but simple Metrology that is the Science of measuring things.</p>
<p>Lazards produce an excellent report on the levelised cost of Electriciity and Energy production and Dr Tim Morgan, (ex-head of research at Tullett Prebon ( not exactly a bunch of Green Hippy Commies) with his SEEDS energy Database look at surplus energy prodcution and its correlation to prosperity.<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/25/energy-economy-renewables-including-nuclear/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/25/energy-economy-renewables-including-nuclear/</a></p>
<p>Energy Cost of Energy is explained here by Dr Tim Morgan.</p>
<p>“SEEDS uses an alternative measure, ECoE (the Energy Cost of Energy), which expresses cost as a percentage of the gross energy accessed. Because the world economy is a closed system, ECoE is not directly analogous to ‘cost’ in the usual financial sense. Rather, it is an economic rent, limiting the choice we exercise over any given quantity of energy. If we have 100 units of energy, and the ECoE is 5%, we exercise choice (or ‘discretion’) over 95 units. If ECoE rises to 10%, we now have discretion over only 90 units, even though the gross amount remains 100.This is loosely analogous to personal prosperity. If someone’s income remains the same, but the cost of essentials rises, that person is worse off, even though income itself hasn’t changed”.</p>
<p>Understanding ECoEECoE evolves over time. In the early stages of any given resource, ECoE is driven downwards by geographic reach, and by economies of scale. Once maturity is reached, depletion takes over as the driver, pushing ECoE upwards.<br />
In the pre-maturity phase, technology accelerates the fall in ECoE driven by reach and scale. Post-maturity, technology acts to mitigate the rise caused by depletion. But – and this is often misunderstood – the capabilities of technology are limited to the envelope of the physical characteristics of the resource.<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/redefining-fiscal-conservatism-the-terra-energy-based-fiscal-unit-fores-and-lagom-white-paper-boundary-conditions-for-a-fiscal-conservatism-based-upon-circular-economics-part-one-scope/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/redefining-fiscal-conservatism-the-terra-energy-based-fiscal-unit-fores-and-lagom-white-paper-boundary-conditions-for-a-fiscal-conservatism-based-upon-circular-economics-part-one-scope/</a></p>
<p>WIth FIAT currencies and floating exchange rates, any money based measure that does not have a properly defined referent is sufficient to render any further analysis using it as its basis at best unreliable but in fact worse than useless, corrupted in every sense of the word in fact.</p>
<p><a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/</a></p>
<p>I look forward to a fruitful Discussion perhaps you will be good enough to expand upon your Critique? 😉</p>
<p>beng135  April 25, 2019 at 7:00 am<br />
Roger, what in the world are you yapping about? AOC has it all over you.</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 11:44 am<br />
beng135, Yapping? I suspect what you are describing fits rater better your short snappy interjection. My own Long Winded efforts may be boring, tedious and ultimately nonsense but Yapping They are not.<br />
Heres the Multi-Media Web Site for my Novel Conquest of Dough,</p>
<p><a href="https://theconquestofdough.weebly.com/the-conquest-of-dough.html" rel="nofollow ugc">https://theconquestofdough.weebly.com/the-conquest-of-dough.html</a></p>
<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 12:36 pm<br />
My own Long Winded efforts may be boring, tedious and ultimately nonsense</p>
<p>Well, at least you have some self-awareness. Kudos for that. (though I don’t think there’s any “may” about it).</p>
<p>Phoenix44  April 25, 2019 at 7:49 am<br />
FIAT currencies – which are actually fiat currencies BTW – BAD BAD BAD.</p>
<p>There we go, shortened your rantings.</p>
<p>A price captures what you need to know – what people are willing to pay for something. A unit of energy does not. Ergo, a unit of energy is a dumb way of working out whether people are doing the right thing economically. I would trade a vast amount of oil for a bottle of water if I was stranded in a desert by a big oil-field, and vice versa if stranded in the desert with a taker full of water and out of petrol.</p>
<p>John Endicott  April 25, 2019 at 9:57 am<br />
Succinctly put and much more coherent that the long form rantings it shortened. Thanks Pheonix44.</p>
<p>Paul  April 25, 2019 at 1:12 pm<br />
Try paying the IRS with non fiat money</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 9:01 pm<br />
You miss the point completely.<br />
A FIAT Currency is absolutely fine what the problem is is the USe of the Fiat currency where the unit of account is not well defined. All Fiat currencies are at present ill-defined rendering all objective pricing and valuation meaningless to the point of absurdity.</p>
<p>See Wes Freeberg #Quanta<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/938457795816579084" rel="nofollow ugc">https://twitter.com/i/moments/938457795816579084</a></p>
<p>roger lewis  April 25, 2019 at 9:29 pm<br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/wesfree/status/938560790117998592" rel="nofollow ugc">https://twitter.com/wesfree/status/938560790117998592</a> do look at the full link but this is a bumper sticker</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: rogerglewis		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-4008</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rogerglewis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 08:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-4008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roger  April 24, 2019 at 8:38 pm
https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/ The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit
basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters-
Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions.
Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again-
https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/

Phoenix44  April 25, 2019 at 7:37 am
No, because it assumes there is a consistent and stable value for the unit of energy – but there is not. A gallon of petrol (gasoline) is worth a vast amount in a Mad Max world and zero in a world that has banned cars.

Natural gas is worth nothing at many oil rigs, so they flare it. At my cooker hob it’s worth far more.

Unlike electronic dollars, moving energy from place to place costs money and energy.

It doesn&#039;t add up...  April 25, 2019 at 3:43 am
So you didn’t read it.

David Middleton  April 25, 2019 at 4:37 am
I like this bit…

It is assumed that ERoEI &#062;5 to 7 is required for modern society to function. This marks the edge of The Net Energy Cliff and it is clear that new Green technologies designed to save humanity from CO2 may kill humanity through energy starvation instead. Fossil fuels remain comfortably away from the cliff edge but march closer to it for every year that passes. The Cheetah symbolises an energy system living on the edge.

The rest is about as useful as looking for “Paul is dead” clues on Beatles albums.

“Society” doesn’t “gather” energy… Businesses do.

David Middleton  April 25, 2019 at 4:54 am
I really like this bit too…

For many months Energy Matters has been plagued by Green Trolls. Symptoms of being a Green Troll are;

e) Posting an unduly large number of comments on a thread.
f) Asking rhetorical questions
g) Focussing on a detail of a post that may be incorrect or debatable and largely irrelevant whilst ignoring the larger body that may be accurate and important to the debate
h) Continually trying to undermine the credibility of the post author
i) Repetition
j) Use of offensive language including the liberal use of the term “denier”

http://euanmearns.com/blog-rules/

I don’t totally disagree with Euan Mearns, Art Berman and other veterans of The Oil Drum. I actually agree with them most of the time. As I explained in Part One of this series, Peak Oil is a real thing… I just don’t think it matters and explained why.

EROEI is a real equation. The problems with it are:

1) Where does the “invested” energy inventory start?
2) Investment in energy production is denominated in $ and other currencies.
3) Return on investment in energy production is denominated in $ and other currencies.

So, it’s a lot like sitting around looking for clues that “Paul is dead” on Beatles albums and song lyrics… It’s like playing Revolution Number 9 backwards.

Johann Wundersamer  April 25, 2019 at 6:47 am
That’s a good one :

“It’s like playing Revolution Number 9 backwards.”

backwards of backwards = highest speed at velocity 0.

Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 5:46 am
@It Doesn’t add up, of course, I read it and I disagree with the fundamental premise that a Dollar based unit of account that is not merely ill-defined but Undefined and arbitrary can be relied upon to pay full market value for our most precious resource, Energy.

Rod  April 25, 2019 at 9:23 am
Our “most precious resource” is air. Try living more than a few minutes without it.

Yet air is, for the most part, free. Why? Because it’s so abundant that no one can make money developing the means to collect it and distribute it. They would have no buyers at any price. So the price of air, zero dollars, tells you exactly what our “most precious resource” is worth despite its importance to life on earth.

And yes, there are exceptions, but they make the case. Spending time underwater requires a source of air. So people are paid to collect it and distribute it. The dollar cost of such air reflects the effort and resources put into making it available despite the air itself being a freely available resource.

The dollar, you see, is a means of comparing apples to oranges, oil to gas, wind power to oil, etc. We muck up the system completely when we start adding value judgements to the process, as we’ve been doing by subsidizing whatever is in favor at the time (wind, solar) and penalizing what is out of favor (coal, nuclear). Let free market prices perform their invaluable function of offering accurate comparisons and get of the way. The rest will take care of itself.

Weylan McAnally  April 25, 2019 at 1:27 pm
Oil is priced only in the US Dollar. That would make it the logical unit of account.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Roger  April 24, 2019 at 8:38 pm<br />
<a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/03/04/the-big-apple-plan-wesley-freeburg-why-abstract-currencies-fail%e2%80%8a/</a> The unit of account in a Fiat money system is an arbitrary unit<br />
basing a unit of account upon an SI Unit of energy makes a great deal of sense if you do not wish to be robbed of your skin in the game by the money laundering Banksters-<br />
Sadly the Author of this piece has gone off at half cock failing to define terms and set boundary conditions.<br />
Watch Glassmans talk and slide show and try again-<br />
<a href="https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/" rel="nofollow ugc">https://www.bitchute.com/video/dv8avoovsHqr/</a></p>
<p>Phoenix44  April 25, 2019 at 7:37 am<br />
No, because it assumes there is a consistent and stable value for the unit of energy – but there is not. A gallon of petrol (gasoline) is worth a vast amount in a Mad Max world and zero in a world that has banned cars.</p>
<p>Natural gas is worth nothing at many oil rigs, so they flare it. At my cooker hob it’s worth far more.</p>
<p>Unlike electronic dollars, moving energy from place to place costs money and energy.</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t add up&#8230;  April 25, 2019 at 3:43 am<br />
So you didn’t read it.</p>
<p>David Middleton  April 25, 2019 at 4:37 am<br />
I like this bit…</p>
<p>It is assumed that ERoEI &gt;5 to 7 is required for modern society to function. This marks the edge of The Net Energy Cliff and it is clear that new Green technologies designed to save humanity from CO2 may kill humanity through energy starvation instead. Fossil fuels remain comfortably away from the cliff edge but march closer to it for every year that passes. The Cheetah symbolises an energy system living on the edge.</p>
<p>The rest is about as useful as looking for “Paul is dead” clues on Beatles albums.</p>
<p>“Society” doesn’t “gather” energy… Businesses do.</p>
<p>David Middleton  April 25, 2019 at 4:54 am<br />
I really like this bit too…</p>
<p>For many months Energy Matters has been plagued by Green Trolls. Symptoms of being a Green Troll are;</p>
<p>e) Posting an unduly large number of comments on a thread.<br />
f) Asking rhetorical questions<br />
g) Focussing on a detail of a post that may be incorrect or debatable and largely irrelevant whilst ignoring the larger body that may be accurate and important to the debate<br />
h) Continually trying to undermine the credibility of the post author<br />
i) Repetition<br />
j) Use of offensive language including the liberal use of the term “denier”</p>
<p><a href="http://euanmearns.com/blog-rules/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://euanmearns.com/blog-rules/</a></p>
<p>I don’t totally disagree with Euan Mearns, Art Berman and other veterans of The Oil Drum. I actually agree with them most of the time. As I explained in Part One of this series, Peak Oil is a real thing… I just don’t think it matters and explained why.</p>
<p>EROEI is a real equation. The problems with it are:</p>
<p>1) Where does the “invested” energy inventory start?<br />
2) Investment in energy production is denominated in $ and other currencies.<br />
3) Return on investment in energy production is denominated in $ and other currencies.</p>
<p>So, it’s a lot like sitting around looking for clues that “Paul is dead” on Beatles albums and song lyrics… It’s like playing Revolution Number 9 backwards.</p>
<p>Johann Wundersamer  April 25, 2019 at 6:47 am<br />
That’s a good one :</p>
<p>“It’s like playing Revolution Number 9 backwards.”</p>
<p>backwards of backwards = highest speed at velocity 0.</p>
<p>Roger G Lewis  April 25, 2019 at 5:46 am<br />
@It Doesn’t add up, of course, I read it and I disagree with the fundamental premise that a Dollar based unit of account that is not merely ill-defined but Undefined and arbitrary can be relied upon to pay full market value for our most precious resource, Energy.</p>
<p>Rod  April 25, 2019 at 9:23 am<br />
Our “most precious resource” is air. Try living more than a few minutes without it.</p>
<p>Yet air is, for the most part, free. Why? Because it’s so abundant that no one can make money developing the means to collect it and distribute it. They would have no buyers at any price. So the price of air, zero dollars, tells you exactly what our “most precious resource” is worth despite its importance to life on earth.</p>
<p>And yes, there are exceptions, but they make the case. Spending time underwater requires a source of air. So people are paid to collect it and distribute it. The dollar cost of such air reflects the effort and resources put into making it available despite the air itself being a freely available resource.</p>
<p>The dollar, you see, is a means of comparing apples to oranges, oil to gas, wind power to oil, etc. We muck up the system completely when we start adding value judgements to the process, as we’ve been doing by subsidizing whatever is in favor at the time (wind, solar) and penalizing what is out of favor (coal, nuclear). Let free market prices perform their invaluable function of offering accurate comparisons and get of the way. The rest will take care of itself.</p>
<p>Weylan McAnally  April 25, 2019 at 1:27 pm<br />
Oil is priced only in the US Dollar. That would make it the logical unit of account.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: The Free Energy Revolution Has Begun &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-2475</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Free Energy Revolution Has Begun &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 06:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-2475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#8230; https://twitter.com/PMotels/status/1122017334183518208 [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230</a>; <a href="https://twitter.com/PMotels/status/1122017334183518208" rel="nofollow ugc">https://twitter.com/PMotels/status/1122017334183518208</a> [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: GALT: The Best Kept Secret in the World that Could Free Humanity with Unlimited Free Energy &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog		</title>
		<link>/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-useful-idiots-for-usury-everywhere-watts-up-with-that-limitstonouse/comment-page-1/#comment-2474</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GALT: The Best Kept Secret in the World that Could Free Humanity with Unlimited Free Energy &#8211; RogersLongHairBlog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 05:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4374#comment-2474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#8230; [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] <a href="https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230" rel="nofollow ugc">https://longhairedmusings.wordpress.com/2019/04/25/clowns-to-the-left-of-me-jokers-to-the-right-usef&#038;#8230</a>; [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
